JOSH FINNIE

□ 860-716-5996 | ☑ josh@jfin.us | ② www.joshfinnie.com | 🛅 joshfinnie

INTRODUCTION

I am a self-taught, highly-skilled software engineer with over 10 years of expertise in various programming languages. My primary focus is on constructing large-scale and intricate APIs, creating interactive websites, and enhancing internal engineering teams through building tools and creating processes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

People Data Labs Senior Software Engineer

May 2023 - Present

PeopleDataLabs has enabled thousands of engineering, data science, product, and other technical teams to build compliant, innovative, people data based software solutions. I work on the Delivery and API team improving how customers interact with our data via API.

Highlighted Successes:

· Developed and maintain the PeopleDataLabs Rust SDK.

Technologies Used: Python (Flask, Django, AWS Lambda), Pulumi, Docker, Rust, AWS RDS (Aurora PostgreSQL), AWS ElastiCache (Redis)

IndigoAg Staff Software Engineer

May 2022 - March 2023

Carbon by Indigo enables farmers to earn income for adopting sustainable practices that lead to the production of high-quality, registry-issued carbon credits. I worked directly with external partners in adopting data into our carbon sesquestration models.

Highlighted Successes:

- · Lead the process from initial architecture to finial development increasing adoption of the carbon sequestration application.
- · Mentored junior developers and build best-practices throughout the engineering department.
- · Wrote technical documentation to improve best-practices for company-wide database backfill proceedure.

Technologies Used: Python (Flask, FastAPI), PostgreSQL, Javascript (React), Docker, Architecture

PBS Senior Software Engineer

September 2019 - May 2022

The Public Brodcasting Service (PBS) is an American public network that provides educational programs across television and the web. I worked on developing the backend of PBS.org where I worked closely with vital projects like device authentication and improved web search functionality.

Highlighted Successes:

- · Lead development in new GraphQL endpoint for content distribution taking into account different team needs.
- · Developed a infrastructure framework for PBS Engineering to unify how services get deployed to AWS.
- · Developed cross-application best practices for code quality and testing infrastructure.

Technologies Used: Python (Django, Graphene), Javascript (React), Go, CSS (Sass), PostgreSQL, Docker, GraphQL, AWS (ECS, ECR)

Skyword (Merged with Trackmaven) Senior Software Engineer

October 2018 - August 2019

Skyword merged with TrackMaven to develop a world-class content development partnership. I led the effort to unify users between the two platforms and implemented best-practices for security upgrades.

Highlighted Successes:

· Developed a cross-platform data exchange between TrackMaven's Django infrastructure and Skyword's Java infrastructure.

Technologies Used: Python (Django), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Kotlin

Trackmaven was the leading social media manager working with Fortune 500 companies to help improve their position in the ever-growing social media space. I joined as engineer #4 and was a jack-of-all-trades working both the frontend and the backend codebase.

Highlighted Successes:

- · Worked as the lead architect on the migration of our base Django application to Python 3 while also upgrading all application dependencies.
- · Planned and architected of our Kubernetes infrastructure introducing better best-practices in deployment through Terraform.
- · Established and led a Quality and Infrastructure engineering team that focuses on promoting sound application infrastructure through ensuring high quality code and developing best practices across the engineering department.

Technologies Used: Python (Django), Javascript (AngularJS, React, Node.js), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Koansys, LLC. Application Developer

February 2012 - March 2014

Highlighted Successes:

- · Developed and deployed the Interactive Satellite Tracker (iSat), an application written in JavaScript that calculates satellite positioning in real-time based off of open-source data for Science@NASA,
- · Designed and built cloud infrastructure and automated scripts using Ansible to migrate Science@NASA's Content Management System to Amazon Web Services and from Django to Drupal.

Technologies Used: Python (Django, Flask), Javascript, Drupal, Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, Route53, Cloudfront, API Gateway)

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

wasm-frontmatter

https://www.npmjs.com/package/wasm-frontmatter

A clone of grey-matter written in Rust. The rust code is used to generate Wasm code and is then released to NPM. My tests have found that Wasm-Frontmatter is three times faster than the javascript equivalent.

PushFile

https://www.npmjs.com/package/pushfile

A project written in Node.js which allows you to push a file to Amazon Web Services S3 and gives you an URL in return. Written using the latest TypeScript syntax and is compiled to ES5 so it works as a command line tool.

JoshFinnie.com https://www.joshfinnie.com

My personal blogging site written using the Astro.Build static site generator. Takes advantage of Tailwind CSS and is hosted on Netlify for high-availability. I write about learnings of software development and tutorials.

More open-source projects found at https://github.com/joshfinnie/

TALKS & PRESENTATIONS

- · Introduction to Python Poetry Indigo Ag Internal Tech Talk, February 1st, 2023
- · Introduction to Asynchronous Python Indigo Ag Internal Tech Talk, December 8th, 2022
- \cdot g
RPC Walkthrough and Programming Showcase PBS Internal Tech Talk, June 23
rd, 2021
- · Building Wasm-Frontmatter RustDC, March 16, 2021
- · Intro to Rust and Wasm for Javascript Developers DC JS, December 9, 2020
- · Docker Multi-stage Builds and other Best Practices PBS Internal Tech Talk, July, 21, 2020

All talks and presentations found at https://www.joshfinnie.com/talks/

EDUCATION

Central Connecticut State University

Classes towards a M.S. in Geography (GIS Track)

University of Connecticut

B.A. in Economics. (Certificate in Quantitative Economics & Minor in Mathematics)